<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Siddharth Jain</title>
    <link>https://sidjain1412.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Siddharth Jain</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Siddharth</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sidjain1412.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mumbai Meri Jaan</title>
      <link>https://sidjain1412.github.io/posts/mumbai/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidjain1412.github.io/posts/mumbai/</guid>
      <description> Mumbai&amp;rsquo;s wildlife is truly amazing and so underappreciated. Most people turn a blind eye to it but it&amp;rsquo;s a true miracle how many different ecosystems thrive in this city.
Carnivores </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why are you building what you&#39;re building?</title>
      <link>https://sidjain1412.github.io/posts/useful-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidjain1412.github.io/posts/useful-features/</guid>
      <description>Every data professional has worked on a dashboard and wanted to cram all sorts of fancy charts/data points in it. Every data professional knows that no one is really going to use the dashboard properly.
They&amp;rsquo;ll still want to make the dashboard as awesome (from their POV) as possible.
Just so y&amp;#39;all know:
Every time you push code, you appear on this real-time wall at the @github HQ. pic.twitter.com/rqfpDPDDjB</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garbett Plateau Trek</title>
      <link>https://sidjain1412.github.io/posts/garbett-trek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidjain1412.github.io/posts/garbett-trek/</guid>
      <description>A relatively easy (but long) trek near Karjat, just 90 minutes from Mumbai and a great weekend getaway
I highly recommend it, so would quite a few folks at CleverTap
Route: Map above has many comments
🗺️ How To Reach: Train: Local train from Ghatkopar to Bhivpuri Road (CSMT→Karjat Fast Train), takes ~90 minutes
Car: Drive to Diksal village, park near Shiv Temple (marked on the map) and descend back to there post the trek.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Streaming OpenAI App in Python</title>
      <link>https://sidjain1412.github.io/posts/streaming-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidjain1412.github.io/posts/streaming-api/</guid>
      <description>In this blog, I’ll go over the basics of FastAPI, Query validations and Streaming APIs , and we’ll build an API that generates a marketing campaign strategy for the brand given in the input.
Read the full blog</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anomaly Detection for Time Series Data</title>
      <link>https://sidjain1412.github.io/posts/anomaly-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidjain1412.github.io/posts/anomaly-detection/</guid>
      <description>The basics of time series data, various types of anomalies in it, and an overview of popular techniques for anomaly detection&amp;hellip;
Read the full blog</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximising Your A/B Test Outcomes with Multi Armed Bandits</title>
      <link>https://sidjain1412.github.io/posts/multi-armed-bandits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidjain1412.github.io/posts/multi-armed-bandits/</guid>
      <description>Traditional A/B testing has stuck around for decades and is an important tool in a marketer’s toolkit, but there also exist other techniques for testing, some that even perform better and combat the flaws of A/B testing. Let’s explore them in this blog&amp;hellip;
Read the full blog</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Analyse Marketing Surveys</title>
      <link>https://sidjain1412.github.io/posts/marketing-surveys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidjain1412.github.io/posts/marketing-surveys/</guid>
      <description>How Do We Find Bivariate Insights From Survey Data?
Create a pivot table/crosstab of the two variables you are considering. Calculate the Chi Square and p value to test for significance of the relationship between the variables. If significant, create heatmaps to find standout insights within the crosstab&amp;hellip; Read the full blog</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Integrity</title>
      <link>https://sidjain1412.github.io/posts/data-integrity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidjain1412.github.io/posts/data-integrity/</guid>
      <description>In today’s era of personalized marketing, a marketer is lost without rich customer data. But what many marketers forget while pushing millions of data points to the cloud is the importance of quality and the integrity of their data points&amp;hellip;
Read the full blog</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
